Finding Aid for Bureau of School Services (University of Michigan) Records 1871-1992
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Accreditation Inspection Reports 1871-1992
  - O-Q
    - Port Huron
      - St. Stephen High School 1914-1964 (Box 126)
    - Portland
      - Portland High School 1905-1992 (Box 126)
      - St. Patrick High School 1953-1991 (Box 126)
    - Posen
      - Posen High School 1944-1980 (Box 126)
    - Potterville
      - Potterville High School 1944-1992 (Box 126)
    - Powers
      - North Central High School (consolidation of Powers-Spalding High School and Hermansville High School) 1971-1975 (Box 126)
      - Powers-Spalding High School 1956-1968 (Box 126)
        (see also Spalding)
    - Prescott
      - Prescott High School 1932-1940 (Box 126)
    - Quincy
      - Quincy High School 1905-1992 (Box 127)
    - Quinnesec
      - Quinnesec High School 1927-1994 (Box 127)
  - R-S
    - Ramsay
      - Bessemer Township Schools 1943 (Box 127)
    - Rapid City
      - Rapid City High School 1935-1940 (Box 127)
    - Rapid River
      - Rapid River High School 1915-1992 (Box 127)
    - Ravenna
      - Ravenna High School 1922-1991 (Box 127)
    - Reading
      - Reading High School (later John E. Owens High School) 1905-1992 (Box 127)
    - Redford
      - Redford Bishop Borgess High School 1980-1992 (Box 128)
      - Redford Catholic Central High School 1980-1992 (Box 128)
      - St. Agatha High School 1956-1991 (Box 128)
      - (Lee M.) Thurston High School 1957-1992 (Box 128)
      - Redford Union High School 1919-1992 (Box 128)
    - Reed City
      - Reed City High School 1905-1992 (Box 129)
    - Reese
      - Reese High School 1926-1992 (Box 129)
    - Remus
      - Chippewa Hills High School [formerly (Mecosta-) Remus High School) 1930-1992 (Box 129)
    - Republic
      - Republic (-Michigamme) High School 1907-1992 (Box 129)
    - Richland
      - Gull Lake High School/Kellogg High School/Richland High School 1923-1992 (Box 130)
        (see also Hickory Corners)
    - Richmond
      - Richmond Community High School 1915-1992 (Box 130)
      - St. Augustine High School 1948-1968 (Box 130)
        (see also Lenox)
    - River Rouge
      - River Rouge High School 1916-1991 (Box 130)
      - Our Lady of Lourdes High School 1920-1974 (Box 130)
    - Riverview
      - Gabriel Richard High School 1968-1992 (Box 130)
      - Riverview Community High School (formerly Albert E. Smith High School) 1931-1992 (Box 131)
    - Rives Junction
      - Henrietta Agricultural School 1952 (Box 131)
    - Rochester
      - Rochester Adams High School 1970-1992 (Box 131)
      - Rochester High School 1915-1992 (Box 131)
    - Rochester Hills
      - Rochester Hills Lutheran High School (NW) 1988-1992 (Box 131)
    - Rock
      - Rock High School (also known as Mid Peninsula School) 1925-1992 (Box 131)
    - Rockford
      - Rockford High School 1917-1992 (Box 132)
    - Rockland
      - Rockland (Township) High School 1907-1946 (Box 132)
    - Rockwood
      - Rockwood High School 1939-1945 (Box 132)
    - Rogers City
      - Rogers City High School (formerly Rogers Township High School) 1916-1992 (Box 132)
    - Romeo
      - Romeo (Senior/Community) High School 1905-1992 (Box 132)
      - Batcheldor Hall 1929-1930 (Box 132)
      - Paton Hall 1927-1934 (Box 132)
    - Romulus
      - Romulus (Senior/Township) High School 1927-1992 (Box 132)
    - Roscommon
      - Gerrish-Higgens High School 1931-1992 (Box 133)
    - Rose City
      - Cumming Township Unit High School (formerly Rose City High School) 1930-1968 (Box 133)
    - Roseville
      - Carl Brablec High School 1970-1988 (Box 133)
      - Charwood High School 1948 (Box 133)
      - Eastland High School 1933-1955 (Box 133)
      - Roseville High School 1924-1992 (Box 133)
      - Sacred Heart High School 1958-1971 (Box 133)
    - Royal Oak
      - (George A.) Dondero High School (formerly Royal Oak High School) 1950-1992 (Box 134)
      - (Clarence M.) Kimball High School 1957-1992 (Box 134)
      - Madison High School 1928-1956 (Box 134)
      - Oak Ridge High School 1927-1929 (Box 134)
      - St. Mary's (Regional) High School 1927-1985 (Box 134)
      - Shrine High School, (formerly Shrine of the Little Flower High School) 1946-1992 (Box 134)
    - Rudyard
      - Rudyard (Township) High School 1926-1992 (Box 135)
    - Ruth
      - Saints Peter and Paul High School 1953-1960 (Box 135)
    - Saginaw
      - Arthur Hill High School 1930-1992 (Box 135)
      - Buena Vista High School 1961-1992 (Box 135)
      - Carrollton High School 1963-1986 (Box 135)
      - (Dwight D.) Eisenhower High School 1972-1986 (Box 135)
      - Heritage High School 1987-1992 (Box 136)
      - Holy Family High School 1927-1930 (Box 136)
      - Holy Rosary High School 1947-1970 (Box 136)
      - (Douglas) MacArthur High School 1964-1986 (Box 136)
      - Michigan Lutheran Seminary 1949 (Box 136)
      - Nouvel Catholic Central High School 1985-1992 (Box 136)
      - Sacred Heart High School 1954 (Box 136)
      - Saginaw High School 1915-1992 (Box 136)
      - Saint Andrew High School 1943-1969 (Box 136)
      - Saint Joseph High School 1926-1971 (Box 136)
      - Saint Mary (Cathedral) High School 1914-1981 (Box 136)
      - Saint Paul High Seminary 1963-1970 (Box 136)
      - Saint Stephen High School 1966-1984 (Box 136)
      - Saints Peter and Paul Area High School 1915-1984 (Box 137)
      - Swan Valley High School 1973-1992 (Box 137)
      - Valley Lutheran High School 1978-1991 (Box 137)
    - Saint Charles
      - Saint Charles (Community) High School 1916-1992 (Box 137)
    - Saint Clair
      - Saint Clair High School 1915-1992 (Box 137)
    - Saint Clair Shores
      - Lake Shore High School 1924-1992 (Box 138)
      - Lakeview High School 1930-1991 (Box 138)
      - Saint Clair River Area Schools 1955 (Box 138)
      - Saint Gertrude High School 1945-1971 (Box 138)
      - South Lake High School 1926-1992 (Box 138)
    - Saint Ignace
      - Lasalle High School 1907-1992 (Box 139)
      - Academy of Our Lady of the Straits 1927-1937 (Box 139)
    - Saint Johns
      - Saint Johns High School 1918-1992 (Box 139)
    - Saint Joseph
      - Lake Michigan High School (formerly St. Joseph Catholic High School) 1926-1992 (Box 139)
    - Saint Louis
      - Saint Louis High School 1917-1992 (Box 140)
    - Saline
      - Saline (Area) High School 1905-1992 (Box 140)
    - Sand Creek
      - Sand Creek High School 1923-1992 (Box 140)
    - Sand Lake
      - Sand Lake High School 1925-1957 (Box 140)
    - Sandusky
      - Sandusky (Community) High School 1915-1992 (Box 140)
    - Sanford
      - Meridian High School 1964-1992 (Box 141)
    - Saranac
      - Saranac High School 1916-1992 (Box 141)
    - Saugatuck
      - Saugatuck High School 1916-1992 (Box 141)
    - Sault Sainte Marie
      - Sault Area High School (formerly Sault Ste. Marine High School) 1915-1992 (Box 141)
      - Loretto Academy 1920-1971 (Box 141)
    - Schoolcraft
      - Schoolcraft High School 1908-1992 (Box 142)
    - Scotts
      - Scotts High School 1931-1940 (Box 142)
    - Scottville
      - Mason County Central High School (formerly Scottville High School) 1906-1992 (Box 142)
    - Sebawaing
      - Sebawaing High School (later Unionville-Sebawaing High School) 1915-1992 (Box 142)
    - Shelby
      - Shelby High School 1906-1992 (Box 142)
    - Shepherd
      - Shepherd High School 1915-1992 (Box 143)
    - Sheridan
      - Sheridan (Rural Agricultural) High School 1925-1962 (Box 143)
    - Six Lakes
      - Belvidere Township High School 1938-1944 (Box 143)
    - Skanee
      - Skanee High School 1928 (Box 143)
    - Snover
      - Snover High School 1927 (Box 143)
    - Southfield
      - Academy of Detroit High School 1987 (Box 143)
      - Alex Manoogian High School 1977-1990 (Box 143)
      - Southfield Christian High School 1974-1992 (Box 143)
      - Southfield Senior High School 1952-1992 (Box 143)
    - Southgate
      - Southgate (Anderson) High School 1962-1992 (Box 143)
      - Aequinas High School 1969-1992 (Box 144)
      - George Schafer High School 1959-1982 (Box 144)
    - South Haven
      - South Haven High School 1906-1992 (Box 144)
    - South Lyon
      - South Lyon High School 1947-1992 (Box 144)
    - South Rockwood
      - South Rockwood High School 1945 (Box 144)
    - Spalding
      - Powers-Spalding High School 1936-1943 (Box 144)
        (see also Powers)
    - Sparta
      - Sparta High School 1916-1992 (Box 145)
    - Spring Arbor
      - Spring Arbor High School/Spring Arbor Academy/Spring Arbor Junior College High School) 1917-1960 (Box 145)
    - Spring Lake
      - Spring Lake High School 1964-1992 (Box 145)
    - Springfield
      - Springfield High School 1957-1990 (Box 145)
    - Springport
      - Springport High School 1923-1992 (Box 145)
    - Springville (see Mesick) (Box 145)
    - Stambaugh
      - Stambaugh High School 1916-1967 (Box 146)
    - Standish
      - Standish (-Sterling) High School 1915-1992 (Box 146)
    - Stanton
      - Central Montcalm High School (formerly Stanton Union High School) 1916-1992 (Box 146)
    - Stephenson
      - Stephenson Area High School 1915-1992 (Box 146)
    - Sterling
      - Sterling High School 1922-1958 (Box 146)
    - Sterling Heights
      - Henry Ford II High School 1975-1992 (Box 146)
      - Sterling Heights High School (Box 147)
      - (Adlai) Stevenson High School 1970-1992 (Box 147)
    - Stevensville
      - Lakeshore High School (Box 147)
    - Stockbridge
      - Stockbridge High School 1916-1992 (Box 147)
    - Sturgis
      - Sturgis (Senior) High School 1917-1992 (Box 148)
    - Sunfield
      - Sunfield Community High School 1930-1960 (Box 148)
    - Suttons Bay
      - Suttons Bay (Rural Agricultural) High School 1916-1992 (Box 148)
    - Swartz Creek
      - Swartz Creek (Community) High School 1929-1992 (Box 148)
  - T-Z
    - Tawas City
      - Tawas (City/Area) High School 1931-1992 (Box 148)
        (see also East Tawas)
    - Taylor
      - (John F.) Kennedy High School 1965-1992 (Box 148)
      - Taylor Center High School 1954-1991 (Box 149)
      - (Harry S.) Truman High School 1974-1992 (Box 149)
    - Tecumseh
      - Tecumseh High School 1905-1992 (Box 149)
    - Tekonsha
      - Tekonsha High School 1916-1976 (Box 149)
    - Temperance
      - Bedford High School 1934-1992 (Box 150)
    - Thompsonville
      - Thompsonville Consolidated High School 1924-1928 (Box 150)
    - Three Oaks
      - River Valley High School (formerly Three Oaks High School) 1907-1991 (Box 150)
    - Three Rivers
      - Three Rivers High School 1905-1992 (Box 150)
    - Traverse City
      - Pathfinder School 1979 (Box 150)
      - St. Francis High School 1918-1992 (Box 150)
      - Traverse City High School 1905-1992 (Box 151)
    - Trenary
      - Trenary (Mathias Township) High School 1922-1960 (Box 151)
    - Trenton
      - Trenton High School (formerly Slocum Truax High School) 1915-1992 (Box 151)
    - Trout Creek
      - Trout Creek Interior Township Schools 1938-1954 (Box 151)
    - Troy
      - Athens High School 1974-1992 (Box 151)
      - Bethany Christian School 1974 (Box 152)
      - Troy High School 1953-1992 (Box 152)
    - Trufant
      - Trufant High School 1938-1940 (Box 152)
    - Tustin
      - Burdell Township Rural Agricultural High School (later Tustin High School and Pine River High School) 1917-1965 (Box 152)
    - Twining
      - Arenac Eastern High School 1948-1992 (Box 152)
    - Ubly
      - Ubly High School 1921-1992 (Box 152)
    - Union City
      - Union City High School 1907-1992 (Box 152)
    - Unionville
      - Unionville-Sebewaing Area Senior High School (formerly Unionville Community High School) 1924-1973 (Box 153)
    - Utica
      - St. Lawrence High School 1958-1971 (Box 153)
      - (Adlai) Stevenson High School 1968-1969 (Box 153)
      - Utica Community High School 1916-1992 (Box 153)
    - Vanderbilt
      - Vanderbilt (Rural Agricultural) School 1951-1992 (Box 153)
    - Van Dyke
      - Lincoln High School 1927-1958 (Box 153)
      - Fitzgerald High School 1950-1959 (Box 153)
    - Vassar
      - Vassar High School 1915-1992 (Box 153)
    - Vermontville
      - Maple Valley High School (formerly Vermontville High School) 1928-1992 (Box 154)
    - Vernon
      - Vernon High School 1929-1938 (Box 154)
    - Vestaburg
      - Vestaburg (Community/Rural Agricultural) High School 1930-1992 (Box 154)
    - Vicksburg
      - Vicksburg High School 1905-1992 (Box 154)
    - Vulcan
      - Vulcan High School 1915-1963 (Box 154)
    - Wakefield
      - Wakefield (Township) High School 1915-1992 (Box 154)
    - Waldron
      - Waldron Area High School 1917-1992 (Box 155)
    - Walkerville
      - Walkerville (Rural Agricultural) High School 1929-1953 (Box 155)
    - Walled Lake
      - Central High School (formerly Walled Lake High School) 1922-1992 (Box 155)
      - Western High School 1970-1992 (Box 155)
    - Warren
      - Bethesda Christian School 1985-1992 (Box 155)
      - (Paul K.) Cousino High School 1964-1992 (Box 155)
      - De La Salle Collegiate High School 1981-1992 (Box 155)
        (see also Detroit)
      - Fitzgerald High School 1960-1992 (Box 156)
      - Lincoln High School 1957-1992 (Box 156)
      - (Charles S.) Mott High School 1969-1992 (Box 156)
      - St. Anne High School 1968-1988 (Box 156)
      - Warren High School 1937-1992 (Box 156)
      - Warren Woods Tower High School 1974-1992 (Box 157)
      - Warren Woods High School 1974-1983 (Box 157)
    - Washington
      - D.D. Eisenhower High School 1972-1992 (Box 157)
    - Wakefield
      - Wakefield Township High School 1984-1985 (Box 157)
    - Waterford
      - Our Lady of the Lakes High School 1965-1992 (Box 157)
      - Waterford-Kettering High School (see Drayton Plains) (Box 157)
      - Waterford Township High School (see Pontiac) (Box 157)
    - Watersmeet
      - Watersmeet High School 1922-1991 (Box 157)
    - Watervliet
      - Watervliet High School 1917-1992 (Box 157)
    - Wayland
      - Wayland (Union) High School 1916-1992 (Box 158)
    - Wayne
      - Saint Mary High School 1952-1971 (Box 158)
      - (Albert E.) Smith High School (see Riverview) (Box 158)
      - Wayne Memorial High School 1915-1992 (Box 158)
    - Webberville
      - Webberville High School 1922-1992 (Box 158)
    - Weidman
      - Weidman High School (formerly Sherman Township High School) 1929-1964 (Box 158)
    - West Bloomfield
      - West Bloomfield High School 1980-1992 (Box 158)
        (see also Keego Harbor)
    - West Branch
      - Ogemaw Heights High School (formerly West Branch High School) 1915-1992 (Box 159)
      - Rose City Area High School 1973-1974 (Box 159)
    - Westland
      - John Glenn High School 1966-1992 (Box 159)
      - Westland Lutheran High School 1989-1992 (Box 159)
    - White Cloud
      - White Cloud High School 1924-1992 (Box 159)
    - Whitehall
      - Whitehall High School 1915-1992 (Box 159)
    - White Pigeon
      - White Pigeon Community High School 1916-1991 (Box 160)
    - White Lake
      - Lakeland High School 1986-1992 (Box 160)
    - White Pine
      - White Pine High School 1961-1992 (Box 160)
    - Whitmore Lake
      - Whitmore Lake High School 1966-1992 (Box 160)
    - Whittemore
      - Whittemore-Prescott Area High School (formerly Burleigh Township Rural Agricultural High School) 1933-1992 (Box 160)
    - Williamston
      - Williamston High School 1907-1992 (Box 160)
    - Wolverine
      - Wolverine High School 1992 (Box 161)
    - Woodland
      - Woodland High School 1924-1961 (Box 161)
    - Wyandotte
      - Our Lady of Mt. Carmel High School 1932-1992 (Box 161)
      - Riverview-Albert E. Smith High School (see Riverview) (Box 161)
      - Riverview-Sibley High School 1930-1960 (Box 161)
      - (Theodore) Roosevelt High School 1916-1992 (Box 161)
      - St. Mary High School 1917 (Box 161)
      - St. Patrick High School 1919-1968 (Box 161)
    - Wyoming
      - Godwin Heights High School 1927-1992 (Box 161)
      - Kelloggsville High School 1981-1992 (Box 162)
      - Lee High School 1925-1992 (Box 162)
      - Rogers High School 1954-1992 (Box 162)
      - Wyoming Park High School 1938-1992 (Box 162)
    - Yale
      - Yale High School 1915-1983 (Box 162)
    - Ypsilanti
      - Lincoln Consolidated High School 1930-1992 (Box 163)
      - Roosevelt High School (State Normal College High School) 1929-1969 (Box 163)
      - St. John the Baptist High School 1964-1969 (Box 163)
      - Willow Run High School 1950-1992 (Box 163)
      - Ypsilanti High School 1905-1992 (Box 163)
    - Zeeland
      - Zeeland High School 1916-1992 (Box 164)
- Detroit High School Study Commission 1966-1968
  The Detroit High School Study Commission series (1966-1968) is comprised of three linear feet of records pertaining to a study of Detroit high schools during the years 1966 to 1968. The student boycott at Northern High School in April of 1966 was the main event evidencing the need for some type of evaluative study leading to change within the high schools of Detroit. The Commission, charged by Detroit Board of Education president Remus Robinson, was to gather thorough, comprehensive, and comparable data for each high school. This data would then be reviewed by the commission, with the expected outcome of establishing recommendations for improvement that would be presented both to the public and the Board of Education. Over 350 citizens were involved in the study, either as members of a high school study committee or as members of the Commission (made up of twenty-six members appointed by the Board of Education, as well as the chairman of each of the high school study committees). Individual school reports were presented to the city-wide Commission, which then brought together the findings and recommendations to be presented to the Board of Education and the public. The final report of the commission is located in box 165.
  The files of the Detroit High School Study Commission include one linear foot of correspondence, inventories of facility needs, guidelines and objectives of the study commission, minutes of Commission meetings, socio-economic rankings, and questionnaires. In addition, there are two linear feet of reports, including miscellaneous reports and statistics (for example, citizens advisory reports and interim reports given by various study committees), individual school reports, and the final reports of the high school study committees that were compiled, bound, and presented to the Detroit Board of Education.
  - Boundary Guides (Box 164)
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous (Box 164)
  - Detroit Board of Education (Box 164)
  - Division for Improvement of Instruction (Box 164)
  - Facilities and Equipment
    - General (Box 164)
    - Inventory of Facility Needs February 1966 (Box 164)
    - Inventory of Facility Needs, revised August 1967 (Box 164)
  - Guidelines and Objectives (Box 164)
  - Minutes 1966-1968 (Box 164)
  - Press Release Information (Box 164)
  - Questionnaires (Box 164)
  - Reports and Statistics
    - Folder 1 (Box 164)
    - Folders 2-6 (Box 165)
      [note: folder 6 contains final commission report for this study]
  - School Reports
    - Final Reports, 3 volumes (Box 165)
    - Individual Reports
      - Cass Tech High School (Box 166)
      - Central High School (Box 166)
      - Chadsey High School (Box 166)
      - Cooley High School (Box 166)
      - Denby High School (Box 166)
      - Eastern High School (Box 166)
      - Finney Junior-Senior High School (Box 166)
      - Kettering High School (Box 166)
      - Mackenzie High School (Box 166)
      - Mumford High School, 2 folders (Box 166)
      - Murray-Wright High School (Box 166)
      - Northeastern High School (Box 166)
      - Northeastern High School (Box 166)
      - Northern High School (Box 166)
      - Northwestern High School (Box 166)
      - Osborn High School (Box 166)
      - Pershing High School (Box 166)
      - Post Junior High School (Box 166)
      - Redford High School (Box 166)
      - Southeastern High School (Box 166)
      - Southwestern High School (Box 166)
      - Western High School (Box 166)
  - Socio-economic rankings (Box 166)
  - Sub-committees
    - General (Box 166)
    - Curriculum and Extracurricular Activities (Box 166)
    - Personnel (Box 166)
    - Relationship between Central Administration and Schools (Box 166)
    - School-Community Relations
      - Study team rosters (Box 166)